Finding Aid for Marguerite Murphy papers, 1901-1949
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Marguerite Murphy papers 1901-1949
Murphy, Marguerite.
4 linear feet
851930 Aa 2
Sister of Michigan public figure Frank Murphy. Correspondence and other papers relating in part to her activities in the Philippines.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of the Hon. George Murphy (donor no. 3074 ).
The collection is open to research. However, researchers must sign the Murphy contract before access to the collection will be given.
Marguerite Murphy was the sister of Detroit mayor, Governor General and US High Commissioner of the Philippines, and Michigan governor, Frank Murphy. During the years when Murphy served in the Philippines, 1933-1935, his sister accompanied him and helped in many of the ceremonial functions of the office.
The collection is divided into two series: Correspondence and Other Papers. The collection is strongest for its documentation of Murphy's service in the Philippines during the mid-1930s. Most of the letters are with her parents and her three brothers.
Subjects:
Detroit (Mich.). Recorder's Court.; Philippines--History--1898-1946.; Murphy, Marguerite.
Contributors:
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murphy, George, 1897-1961.; Teahan, William.
- Correspondence, 1901-1949
  - 1901-1934, 13 folders (Box 1)
  - 1934-1949 and undated, 19 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated, 10 folders (Box 3)
- Other papers
  - Miscellanea, undated, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Travel books, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Address book (Box 4)
  - Diary (Box 4)
  - Telegrams of sympathy (sample) sent to George Murphy and Marguerite Murphy Teahan upon the death of their brother Frank Murphy, July 1949, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Letters of condolences and responses sent to George Murphy and Marguerite Murphy Teahan upon the death of their brother Frank Murphy, July 1949, 8 folders (Box 4)